Guide to the Frank Foster Papers, 1930-2013 and undated, bulk 1950s-2009 RL.00408
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Frank Foster papers
1930-2013 and undated, bulk 1950s-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Foster, Frank, 1928-2011
RL.00408
60.5 Linear Feet
Frank B. Foster III is a saxophonist, flautist, big band leader, educator, and Grammy Award-winning jazz composer and arranger, professionally active in music since the 1940s. The Frank Foster Papers consist chiefly of scores and parts composed or arranged by Foster for big bands and other large jazz ensembles from the 1950s through 2009. Also present are personal files consisting of correspondence, photographs, business records, publicity, reviews, and news clippings; and subject files on musical collaborations, music teaching, organizations and individuals, and family history.
Approximately 2,050 items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Frank Foster Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009, 2010, and 2017.
Biographical Note
Frank B. Foster, III was born in Cincinnati, Ohio on September 23, 1928. He attended Wilberforce University and in 1949 moved to Detroit and began playing in jazz clubs with musicians such as Wardell Gray. He was drafted into the military in 1951 and served in Korea.
In the early 1950s his first two solo albums were released on Blue Note Records: Here Comes Frank Foster (1953) and New Faces, New Sounds (1954). He was a member of the Count Basie Orchestra from 1953-1964, contributing both arrangements and original compositions including the well-known Shiny Stockings, Down for the Count, Blues Backstage, Back to the Apple, and Discommotion, as well as arrangements for the band's Easin' It album. Foster has also performed in bands including The Lloyd Price Big Band, Lionel Hampton and his Orchestra, Woody Herman and his Orchestra, The Thad Jones/Mel Lewis Orchestra, and Elvin Jones's Jazz Machine. By the 1970s Foster formed several groups on his own, including The Non-Electric Company, Living Color and The Loud Minority. In 1980, Foster's Lake Placid Suite was performed as a part of the Winter Olympic Games, and in 1983 Dizzy Gillespie personally commissioned Foster to orchestrate one of the jazz icon's compositions, Con Alma, for a scheduled performance and recording with The London Philharmonic Orchestra directed by Robert Farnon. In 1986 Foster succeeded Thad Jones as the leader of the Count Basie Orchestra, and remained with the band until 1995. During that time he won two Grammy Awards for his arrangements of Deedles' Blues (1987) and Basie's Bag (1988).
Foster's career also included a strong interest in teaching. In 1971 he served as Artist-In-Residence for the New England Conservatory of Music. He also began teaching music for the N.Y. Public Schools in Harlem under the Title I program, Cultural Enrichment Through Music, Dance, and Song. From 1972 to 1976, Foster was an Assistant Professor in the Black Studies Program at the State University of New York at Buffalo (SUNY). He has also worked as an adjunct professor at institutions including The New School for Social Research and New York University. In 1987, he was awarded an honorary doctorate by Central State (formerly Wilberforce) University.
During his long musical career, Foster has been commissioned to compose and arrange works for The Carnegie Hall Jazz Ensemble, The Detroit Civic Symphony Orchestra, The Jazzmobile Corporation of New York City, The Lincoln Center Jazz Orchestra, The Thad Jones/Mel Lewis Orchestra, The Harpers Ferry Historical Association, The Chicago Jazz Ensemble, and many others. In 2002 Foster received the Jazz Masters Award from the National Endowment for the Arts.
In 2001 he suffered a stroke that impaired his left side and caused him to cease performing on saxophone. He continues to compose and arrange for a variety of bands and leads a revival of The Loud Minority in limited engagements.
Selected Discography
1953 Here Comes Frank Foster (Blue Note)
1954 New Faces, New Sounds (Blue Note)
1956 Two Franks Please! (Savoy)
1956 No Count (Savoy)
1963 Basie Is Our Boss (Argo)
1965 Fearless Frank Foster (Prestige)
1969 Frank Foster (Blue Note)
1974 The Loud Minority (Mainstream)
1977 Shiny Stockings (Denon)
1979 Non-Electric Company (EPM Musique)
1982 The House That Love Built (SteepleChase)
1983 Two for the Blues (Pablo/OJC)
1984 Frankly Speaking (Concord Jazz)
1995 A Fresh Taste of Thad Jones and Frank Foster (Hanssler Classics)
1996 Leo Rising (Arabesque)
1998 Swing (live) (Challenge)
2002 Live at Feuerwache Mannheim (Bassic)
2003 We Do It Diff'rent (live) (Mapleshade)
2005 Endless Fingers (Arabesque
2007 Well Water (Piadrum)
Collection Overview
The Frank Foster Papers span the dates 1930 to 2013, with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1950s to 2009. The papers consist chiefly of scores and parts composed or arranged by Foster for big bands and other large jazz ensembles, including works written for the Count Basie Orchestra in the 1950s-1960s and again in the 1980s-1990s, as well as works for The Loud Minority, and numerous other bands and organizations for which Foster was commissioned to compose. The collection is arranged in the following series: Compositions by Frank Foster, Compositions by Others, Personal Files, and Audio and Moving Image Materials. The compositions series are organized into Letter-Sized, Legal-Sized and Oversized subseries. The personal files consist of autobiographical writings, correspondence, photographs, business records, publicity, reviews, and news clippings; and subject files on musical collaborations, music teaching, organizations and individuals, and family history. Audio and moving image materials are primarily concert recordings featuring Foster from the 1970s through the 1990s. Acquired as part of the Jazz Archive at Duke University.
Music -- Instruction and study; Jazz musicians; Jazz; Composers -- United States; Swing (Music); Saxophonists -- United States; Foster, Frank, 1928-2011; Loud Minority (Musical group); Count Basie Orchestra
- Compositions by Foster Series, 1930-2009 and undated, 27 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of manuscript scores and instrumental parts for works composed and arranged by Frank Foster, arranged into three subseries: Letter-Sized Materials, Legal-Sized Materials, and Oversized Materials. Within each subseries, manuscripts are organized alphabetically by title, where different versions and copies of the same composition are grouped together. Many manuscripts are undated. Collection includes hand-written manuscripts, photocopies, and manuscripts produced on a laser printer. Incomplete manuscripts, unidentified pages and fragments are filed in a separate group at the end of the Compositions by Others series.
  Many scores and parts are unbound; please handle carefully and keep pages in their original order.
  - Letter-Sized Materials, 12 boxes
    - An' All Such Stuff As Dat. 1985 (Box 1)
    - Arden Park (Motor City Memories, 2nd movement), 2003 (Box 1)
    - Back To The Apple, undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Bass In Yo' Face, 1995 (Box 1)
    - The Battle We Wage, 2006, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Billion Dollar Bill, 2007, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Blues In Frankie's (Hoss') Flat, 1958, 1986, undated, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Bob's Ransom, 2008 (Box 1)
    - Booze Brothers, 1989, undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Bottom Line (Placid Moments), undated (Box 1)
    - Bring On Th' Raindrops, undated (Box 1)
    - The Bronzed Buckeye, 2009, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Brotherly Shove, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Cecilia Is Love, 1971, 2008, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - The Charltonian Mode, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Chiquito Loco, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Chi-Town Is My Town, 2009 (Box 2)
    - Cidade Alta, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Clanks, 1994, 1997, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Come On In, 1992, 1995, undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Come On In, 1992, 1995, undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Crude Chromaticism, undated (Box 3)
    - Dance On, Frankie Manning, 2009 (Box 3)
    - Dayspring, 1978, 1979, 1996, undated, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Dayspring (continued), 1978, 1979, 1996, undated, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Derricksterity, 1997 (Box 3)
    - Didn' You, 1956, 1956/1984, 2003, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Discommotion, 1962, 1994, undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Discommotion, 1962, 1994, undated, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Down For The Count, 1954, 1982, 1994 (Box 4)
    - Easin' it, 1960, undated, 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Esta Noche, 2002 (Box 4)
    - Flute Of The Room, 1992, undated, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - For All Intents and Purposes, undated (Box 4)
    - Forrest Fire, undated (Box 4)
    - Fos Alarm, 2010 (Box 4)
    - Four Five Six, 1994, 1960, undated, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Fresh Taste Of Blues, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Gone [Go'n] An' Git It Y'all, 1989, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Gotta' Find A Way, 1996, 2002, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Gray Thursday, 1996 (Box 5)
    - The Hampton Strut, 1992 (Box 5)
    - The Heat Of Winter, 1985, undated, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - House That Love Built, undated (Box 5)
    - I'm Outta Here, 2008, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - I Love You Based on Your Availability, 2008, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Insiders Report, 2010, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - It's All About My Jesus, 2009 (Box 6)
    - The Jacoby Jump, 2008, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Jammin' At The Bluebird Inn, 2003, undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Janie Huk, undated, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - John R. And Garfield, 1994, 2002, undated, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Karmageddon, undated (Box 6)
    - Katherine The Great, 1989, undated, 4 folders (Box 6)
    - King Character, 2002, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Lady Carolyn, 1987, 1989, 1 folder (Box 6)
    - Lady Carolyn, 1987, 1989, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - The Lady Is A Trip, 2008 (Box 7)
    - Leo Rising, undated, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Little Chicago Fire, 1987, 1994, 5 folders (Box 7)
    - Lord Of Might, 2002 (Box 7)
    - Love Handles, 1989, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Lover, undated (Box 7)
    - Major Butts, 1992, undated, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Manhattan Fever, undated (Box 8)
    - The Niagara Suite, 1st movement, "The Spirit of John Brown", 2006, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - The Niagara Suite, 2nd movement, "Conference Time", 2006, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - North End Blues, 2003, undated, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Ode To Joe Newman, 1986, 1992, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Placid Moments, 2000 (Box 8)
    - The Precious Blood Of The Saviour, 2006, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Ready Now That You Are, G. B., 1987, 1989, undated, 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Romance Without Sub-Stance, 2008 (Box 9)
    - The Scene Was Mean (Motor City Memories, 1st movement), 2003 (Box 9)
    - Sean's Jones Comes Down, 2004, undated, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Shihtsu-Mon (The Question), Japanese Suite, 1st movement, 1994, undated, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Shiny Stockings, 1955, 1983, 1987, 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Simone, 1971, 1994, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Simone, 1971, 1994, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Skull-Doug-Ery, 1995, 1999 (Box 10)
    - Someone Is Rocking My Jazzboat, undated, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Song Of The Vanquished (Lake Placid Suite Part 3, Section 1), 1982, undated (Box 10)
    - State Of The Art Swing, 1988, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Tahn-Kyu [Tan-Kyu] (The Search), 1994, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Tenors In Heat, undated (Box 10)
    - That's The Kind Of Love, undated (Box 10)
    - Thru' An' Thru' Wit' Freddy Fru (Motor City Memories, 3rd movement), 2003 (Box 10)
    - Thruway Traffic, 1971, undated, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Time Constraints Be Damned, 2004, 2006, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Time Constraints Be Damned, 2004, 2006, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Tomorrow's Blues Today, 1965, 1993, undated, 4 folders (Box 11)
    - Transition, 1989, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Updown Recollections, undated (Box 11)
    - Victorious Blues, undated, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Viva Terrassa, 2004 (Box 11)
    - We Be Jammin', 1989 (Box 11)
    - Well Water, undated (Box 11)
    - Where Nations Meet (Lake Placid Suite, Part 1), undated (Box 11)
    - Who, Me?, 1960, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Winners, 1978, 1988, undated, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Yeah, Right, 2005, undated, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Yo Recuerdo A Mi Hermano Tito, 2005, 2006, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - You Got It, 1994, undated, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Legal-Sized Materials, 3 boxes
    - Cecilia Is Love, undated (Box 45)
    - Ceaseless Blues, undated (Box 45)
    - Easin' It, 1996 (Box 45)
    - Four Five Six, undated (Box 45)
    - A Fresh Taste Of Blues, undated, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Gotta' Find A Way (To Meet Up With Th' Lord), undated (Box 45)
    - Here's To Love Again, Lyrics by William Toran, 1979 (Box 45)
    - Hip Shakin', undated (Box 45)
    - How I Spent The Night, undated (Box 45)
    - Jammin' At The Bluebird Inn (Motor City Memories, 2nd movement, Finale), 2003 (Box 45)
    - Just One Of Those Things, undated (Box 45)
    - Katherine The Great, undated (Box 45)
    - How I Spent The Night, undated (Box 45)
    - Legends of Jazz, 1997 (Box 45)
    - Mirror Lake, undated (Box 46)
    - Ode To Joe Newman, undated, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - One Frank On A Roll, undated (Box 46)
    - Papa Fos', Composed by Frank Foster and Danny Mixon, undated (Box 46)
    - Placid Moments (Lake Placid Suite, Part 3, Section 2), undated (Box 46)
    - The Rare Butterfly, undated (Box 46)
    - Shihtsu-Mon (The Question), Japanese Suite, 1st movement, 1994 (Box 46)
    - Shiny Stockings, undated (Box 46)
    - Simone, undated, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Someone's Rocking My Jazzboat, undated, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Song of the Vanquished (Lake Placid Suite, Part 3, Section 1), undated (Box 47)
    - Sugar Hill Slalom (Lake Placid Suite, Part 7), undated (Box 47)
    - Theme In Search Of A Love Scene, undated, 4 folders (Box 47)
    - Uptown Recollections, undated (Box 47)
    - We Be Jammin' (Count Basie Remembrance Suite, Part 1), 1989 (Box 47)
    - Well Water, undated (Box 47)
    - Where Nations Meet (Lake Placid Suite, Part 1), undated (Box 47)
    - Whiteface Mountain (Lake Placid Suite, Part 3), undated (Box 47)
    - Yes Lord I'm A Sinner, undated (Box 47)
  - Oversized Materials, 12 boxes
    - Arden Park (Motor City Memories, 2nd movement), 2002 (Box 14)
    - Baby Ann, undated (Box 14)
    - Back To The Apple, undated, 2 copies (Box 14)
    - Bass In Yo' Face, 1992, 2 copies (Box 14)
    - Blues In Frankie's Flat, undated, 2 copies (Box 14)
    - Booze Brothers, 1987, 1988, undated, 3 copies (Box 14)
    - Brotherly Shove, 1992, undated (Box 14)
    - Cecilia Is Love, 1990, undated, 5 copies (Box 14)
    - Cidade Alta, 1997, undated, 2 copies (Box 15)
    - Clean Heart Right Spirit, undated, 2 copies (Box 15)
    - Come On In, 1993, 3 copies (Box 15)
    - Crude Chromaticism, undated (Box 15)
    - Dayspring, 1988, 2 copies (Box 16)
    - Derricksterity, 1995, undated, 2 copies (Box 16)
    - Discommotion, undated, 2 copies (Box 16)
    - Down For The Count, undated, 2 copies (Box 16)
    - Easin' It, undated, 3 copies (Box 16)
    - Flute Of The Room, 1991, 3 copies (Box 17)
    - Four, Five, Six, undated (Box 17)
    - A Fresh Taste Of Blues, undated, 4 copies (Box 17)
    - Gotta' Find A Way To Meet Up Wit' Th' Lord, undated (Box 17)
    - The Hampton Strut, undated (Box 17)
    - Hip Shakin', 1993, 4 copies (Box 17)
    - How I Spent The Night, 1991 (Box 18)
    - I Wanna Be Pure, undated (Box 18)
    - Jean Marie, 1977 (Box 18)
    - Katherine The Great, undated, 2 copies (Box 18)
    - Lady Carolyn (Count Basie Remembrance Suite, Part 2), 1988, 3 copies (Box 18)
    - Leo Rising, undated (Box 19)
    - Little Chicago Fire, 1991, undated, 3 copies (Box 19)
    - The Loud Minority, 1976 (Box 19)
    - Love Handles, 1996, 2 copies (Box 19)
    - Major Butts, undated, 3 copies (Box 20)
    - Manhattan Fever, 1968 (Box 20)
    - Mirror Lake, undated, 2 copies (Box 20)
    - Misunderstood Blues, undated (Box 20)
    - Ode To Joe Newman, 1992, 3 copies (Box 20)
    - Old Games, New Faces (Lake Placid Suite, Part 4), undated, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - One Frank On A Roll, undated (Box 21)
    - Papa Fos', undated, 2 copies (Box 21)
    - Placid Moments (Lake Placid Suite, Part 3, Section 2), 1980, 1991, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - The Rare Butterfly, 1959, 1994 (Box 21)
    - Ready Now That You Are, G. B., 1989, undated, 6 copies (Box 22)
    - Requiem For Dusty, undated (Box 22)
    - The Scene Was Mean (Motor City Memories, 1st movement), 2002 (Box 22)
    - Shadowland, undated (Box 22)
    - Shiny Stockings, 1983, undated, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Skull-Doug-Ery, 1993 (Box 23)
    - Someone Is Rocking My Jazzboat, undated (Box 23)
    - Song Of The Vanquished (Lake Placid Suite, Part 3, Section 1), undated (Box 23)
    - Square-Ass Key Date Boogie, 1992 (Box 23)
    - State Of The Art Swing (Count Basie Remembrance Suite, Part 3), 1989, 2 copies (Box 23)
    - Sugar Hill Slalom (Lake Placid Suite, Part 7), 1980, 1991, undated, 3 copies (Box 23)
    - Tahn-Kyu (The Search), 1992 (Box 23)
    - Tenors In Heat, 1988, 1990, 2 copies (Box 24)
    - That's The Kind Of Love (I'm Talking About), 1991, 3 copies (Box 24)
    - Theme In Search Of A Love Scene, undated, 3 copies (Box 24)
    - There'll Be a Time, undated (Box 24)
    - Victorious Blues, 1980, 1986 (Box 24)
    - We Be Jammin' (Count Basie Remembrance Suite, Part 1), 1968, 1989, 2 copies (Box 24)
    - Well Water, undated (Box 24)
    - Where Nations Meet (Lake Placid Suite, Part 1), undated (Box 24)
    - White Face Mountain (Lake Placid Suite, Part 3), 1980 (Box 36)
    - Who, Me? undated, 2 copies (Box 36)
    - Winners, 1992, 2 copies (Box 36)
    - Yes Lord I'm A Sinner (The Great and Terrible Day of the Lord), 1992 (Box 36)
    - You Got It, undated, 3 copies (Box 36)
- Compositions by Others Series, 1930-2004 and undated, 24 boxes
  Foster's arrangements of compositions by Count Basie, Hoagy Carmichael, Nat King Cole, John Coltrane, Duke Ellington, Bill Evans, George Gershwin, Antonio Jobim, Thelonious Monk, and many others. Compositions are arranged in four subseries: Letter-Sized Materials, Legal-Sized Materials, Oversized Materials, and Miscellaneous Manuscripts, which includes manuscript fragments of compositions by Foster, by others, and of unknown authorship. Within each subseries, manuscripts are organized alphabetically by title, where different versions and copies of the same composition are grouped together. Many manuscripts are undated. Collection includes hand-written manuscripts, photocopies, and manuscripts produced on a laser printer. Many are unbound; please handle carefully and keep pages in their original order.
  - Letter-Sized Materials, 6 boxes
    - 61st and Richit. Jones, Thad, undated (Box 13)
    - Airegin. Rollins, (Walter Theodore) Sonny, undated (Box 13)
    - Alligator Boogaloo. Donaldson, Lou, undated (Box 13)
    - Almost Like Being In Love. Loewe, Frederick. Lyrics by Alan Lay Lerner, undated (Box 13)
    - Autumn In New York. Duke, Vernon, undated (Box 13)
    - Autumn Leaves. Kosma, Joseph. Lyrics by Jacques Prévert (English words by Johnny Mercer), undated, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Back To The Apple. Basie, William Count, and Frank Foster, undated (Box 13)
    - Basie Excerpt No. 2, "Corner Pocket". Green, Freddie, 2004 (Box 13)
    - Basie Excerpt No. 4, "Lil' Darlin'". Hefti, Neal, 2004, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Blue In Green. Evans, Bill, undated (Box 13)
    - Blue Sunday. Talley, Gary, undated (Box 13)
    - Body and Soul. Green, Johnny. Lyrics by Edward Heyman, Robert Sour, and Frank Eyton undated (Box 13)
    - Brilliant Corners. Monk, Thelonious Sphere, undated (Box 13)
    - Ceora. Morgan, Lee, undated (Box 13)
    - Chega Da Saudade (No More Blues). Jobim, Antonio Carlos. Lyrics by Moraes, M. Vinicius, Jessie Cavanaugh, and Jon (John Carl) Hendricks, 1962, 1967, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Chelsea Bridge. Strayhorn, Billy, 1941, 1942, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - The Christmas Song. Tormé, Melvin Howard. Lyrics by Robert Wells, undated (Box 13)
    - Con Alma. Gillespie, John Birks Dizzy, undated (Box 13)
    - The Count. Griffin, Johnny,1990 (Box 13)
    - Dark Shadows. Cobert, Robert. Arranged by Ernie Andrews, undated, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Dolphin Dance. Hancock, Herbie, undated (Box 13)
    - Emily. Johnny Mandel, 1964 (Box 66)
    - The End Of A Love Affair. Redding, Edward, undated (Box 13)
    - Epistrophy. Monk, Thelonious, and Kenny Clarke. Lyrics by Kenneth S. Clark, and Cootie Williams, undated (Box 13)
    - Feelin' No Evil. Stubblefield, Clyde, undated (Box 13)
    - Fee-Fi-Fo-Fum. Shorter, Wayne. Lyrics by Patricia Beysens, undated (Box 13)
    - Firm Roots. Walton, Cedar, undated, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Firm Roots. Walton, Cedar, undated, 1 folders (Box 40)
    - For My Lady. Thompson, Gerald, undated (Box 40)
    - Fostradamus. Gardner, Derrick, undated (Box 40)
    - Giant Steps. Coltrane, John, undated (Box 40)
    - The Girl from Ipanema. Jobim, Antonio Carlos. Lyrics by Vinicius de Moraes (English words by Norman Gimbel), undated, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - A Handful Of Stars. Shapiro, Ted. Lyrics by Jack Lawrence, undated (Box 40)
    - Have Yourself A Merry Little Christmas. Martin, Hugh. Lyrics by Ralph Blane, undated (Box 40)
    - Here's That Rainy Day. Van Heusen, Jimmy. Lyrics by Johnny Burke, undated (Box 40)
    - How Great Thou Art. Undated (Box 40)
    - How Insensitive. Jobim, Antônio Carlos. Lyrics by Vinicius de Moraes, 1963/1964, 1964, undated, 3 folders (Box 40)
    - If I Should Lose You. Rainger, Ralph. Lyrics by Leo Robin, undated, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - I'll Close My Eyes. Reid, Billy. Lyrics by Buddy Kaye, undated (Box 40)
    - Impressions. Coltrane, John, undated (Box 40)
    - In A Mello[w] Tone. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke. Lyrics by Gabler Milt, undated, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - In A Sentimental Mood. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke, undated (Box 41)
    - Invitation. Kaper, Bronislau, undated (Box 41)
    - It Don't Mean A Thing. Ellington, Edward Kennedy Duke. Lyrics by Irving Mills, undated (Box 41)
    - It's Only A Paper Moon. Arlen, Harold, and E. Y. Harburg. Lyrics by Billy Rose, undated (Box 41)
    - I've Grown Accustomed To Her Face. Loewe, Frederick. Lyrics by Alan Lay Lerner, undated, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Jeannine. Pearson, Duke, 1960 (Box 41)
    - Joy To The World. Handel, George Frideric, 1981 (Box 41)
    - Just Friends. Klenner, John. Lyrics by Samuel M. Lewis, undated, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Kiss and Run. Ledru, Jack. Lyrics by René Denoncin, undated (Box 41)
    - Lady Bird. Dameron, Tadd (Tadley Ewing Peake), undated (Box 41)
    - Lazy Bird. Coltrane, John, undated (Box 41)
    - Let The Good Times Roll. Jordan, Louis, undated (Box 41)
    - Lightly Stroking. Undated (Box 41)
    - Lotus Blossom. Strayhorn, Billy, undated, 3 folders (Box 41)
    - Love At Sundown. Bhumibol Adulyadej, His Majesty The King, undated, 3 folders (Box 41)
    - Love Walked In. Gershwin, George. Lyrics by Ira Gershwin, undated (Box 42)
    - Lover Come Back To Me. Romberg, Sigmund. Lyrics by Oscar Hammerstein, undated (Box 42)
    - Magic Beams. Bhumibol Adulyadej, His Majesty The King, undated (Box 42)
    - Mambo Inn. Bauza, Mario, undated (Box 42)
    - Mean What You Say. Jones, Thad, undated (Box 42)
    - The Moment Of Truth. Satterwhite, Collen Gray. Lyrics by Frank Scott, undated (Box 42)
    - Moonlight In Vermont. Suessdorf, Karl. Lyrics by John M. Blackburn, undated, 4 folders (Box 42)
    - More Than You Know. Youmans, Vincent (Coleman, Earl). Lyrics by Edward Eliscu, and Billy Rose, undated (Box 42)
    - My Funny Valentine. Rogers, Richard. Lyrics by Lorenz Hart, undated (Box 42)
    - My One And Only Love. Wood, Guy. Lyrics by Robert Mellin, undated, 2 folders (Box 42)